spgpromos.com 2018-08-14

# Starwood Hotels & Resorts

**Last Updated May 18, 2018**

The [Marriott Group,](https://www.marriott.com/Media/PDF/Foreign%20Subsidiaries%20-%20Country%20of%20Incorporation/2015%2010K_Entity%20Only.pdf) which includes Marriott International, Inc., Starwood Hotels & Resorts Worldwide, LLC (formerly known as Starwood Hotels & Resorts Worldwide, Inc.) and their affiliates, values you as our guest and recognizes that privacy is important to you. We want you to be familiar with how we collect, use and disclose data.

This Privacy Statement describes the privacy practices of the Marriott Group for data that we collect:

  * through websites operated by us from which you are accessing this Privacy Statement, including Marriott.com and other websites owned or controlled by the Marriott Group (collectively, the “Websites”)
  * through the software applications made available by us for use on or through computers and mobile devices (the “Apps”)
  * through our social media pages that we control from which you are accessing this Privacy Statement (collectively, our “Social Media Pages”)
  * through HTML-formatted email messages that we send you that link to this Privacy Statement and through your communications with us
  * when you visit or stay as a guest at one of our properties, or through other offline interactions

Collectively, we refer to the Websites, the Apps and our Social Media Pages, as the “Online Services” and, together with offline channels, the “Services.” By using the Services, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Statement.

## Collection of Personal Data

“Personal Data” are data that identify you as an individual or relate to an identifiable individual.

At touchpoints throughout your guest journey, we collect Personal Data in accordance with law, such as: 

  * Name
  * Gender
  * Postal address
  * Telephone number
  * Email address
  * Credit and debit card number or other payment data
  * Financial information in limited circumstances
  * Language preference
  * Date and place of birth
  * Nationality, passport, visa or other government-issued identification data
  * Important dates, such as birthdays, anniversaries and special occasions
  * Membership or loyalty program data (including co-branded payment cards, travel partner program affiliations)
  * Employer details
  * Travel itinerary, tour group or activity data
  * Prior guest stays or interactions, goods and services purchased, special service and amenity requests
  * Geolocation information
  * Social media account ID, profile photo and other data publicly available, or data made available by linking your social media and loyalty accounts

In more limited circumstances, we also may collect:

  * Data about family members and companions, such as names and ages of children
  * Biometric data, such as digital images
  * Images and video and audio data via: (a) security cameras located in public areas, such as hallways and lobbies, in our properties; and (b) body-worn cameras carried by our loss prevention officers and other security personnel
  * Guest preferences and personalized data (“Personal Preferences”), such as your interests, activities, hobbies, food and beverage choices, services and amenities of which you advise us or which we learn about during your visit

If you submit any Personal Data about other people to us or our Service Providers (e.g., if you make a reservation for another individual), you represent that you have the authority to do so and you permit us to use the data in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

Back to Top

## How We Collect Personal Data

We collect Personal Data in a variety of ways:

  * **Online Services.** We collect Personal Data when you make a reservation, purchase goods and services from our Websites or Apps, communicate with us, or otherwise connect with us or post to social media pages, or sign up for a newsletter or participate in a survey, contest or promotional offer.
  * **Property Visits and Offline Interactions.** We collect Personal Data when you visit our properties or use on-property services and outlets, such as restaurants, concierge services, health clubs, child care services, and spas. We also collect Personal Data when you attend promotional events that we host or in which we participate, or when you provide your Personal Data to facilitate an event. 
  * **Customer Care Centers.** We collect Personal Data when you make a reservation over the phone, communicate with us by email, fax or via online chat services or contact customer service. These communications may be recorded for purposes of quality assurance and training.
  * **Owners and Franchisees.** We collect Personal Data from Owners of Marriott Group branded properties that we manage. We also collect Personal Data from Franchisees of Marriott Group branded properties that are independently owned and operated under a franchise agreement with us. Owners and Franchisees are independent from the Marriott Group.
  * **Authorized Licensees.** We collect Personal Data from companies when we enter into a license or similar agreement to sell goods and services under a Marriott Group brand (“Authorized Licensees”). Examples of Authorized Licensees include our time share partners, Marriott Vacations Worldwide Corporation and Vistana Signature Experiences, Inc. Examples of other Authorized Licensees include Cruise Yacht Optco Ltd. d/b/a The Ritz-Carlton Yacht Collection, developers of Marriott Group branded real estate and co-branded credit card partners. Authorized Licensees are independent from the Marriott Group.
  * **Strategic Business Partners.** We collect Personal Data from companies with whom we partner to provide you with goods, services or offers based upon your experiences at our properties or that we believe will be of interest to you (“Strategic Business Partners”). Examples of Strategic Business Partners include on-property outlets, travel and tour partners, time share partners, rental car providers and travel booking platforms. Strategic Business Partners are independent from the Marriott Group.
  * **Other Sources.** We collect Personal Data from other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners and other third parties.
  * **Internet-Connected Devices.** We collect Personal Data from internet-connected devices available in our properties. For example, a smart home assistant may be available for your use and to tailor your accommodations and experience.
  * **Physical & Mobile Location-Based Services.** We collect Personal Data if you download one of our Apps or choose to participate in certain programs. For example, we may collect the precise physical location of your device by using satellite, cell phone tower, WiFi signals, or other technologies. We will collect this data if you opt in through the App or other program (either during your initial login or later) to receive the special offers and to enable location-driven capabilities on your mobile device. If you have opted-in, the App or other program will continue to collect location data when you are in or near a participating property until you log off or close application (i.e., the App or other program will collect this data if it is running in the background) or if you use your phone’s or other device’s setting to disable location capabilities for the Marriott Group App or other program.

Back to Top

## Collection of Other Data

“Other Data” are data that generally do not reveal your specific identity or do not directly relate to an individual. To the extent Other Data reveal your specific identity or relate to an individual, we will treat Other Data as Personal Data. Other Data include:

  * Browser and device data
  * App usage data
  * Data collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies
  * Demographic data and other data provided by you
  * Aggregated data

Back to Top

## How We Collect Other Data

We collect Other Data in a variety of ways:

  * **Your browser or device.** We collect certain data through your browser or automatically through your device, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, internet browser type and version and the name and version of the Online Services (such as the Apps) you are using. We use this data to ensure that the Online Services function properly. 
  * **Your use of the Apps.** We collect certain data when you download and use an App, such as App usage data, the date and time the App on your device accesses our servers and what data and files have been downloaded to the App based on your device number. 
  * **Cookies.**

We collect certain data from cookies, which are pieces of data stored directly on the computer or mobile device that you are using. Cookies allow us to collect data such as browser type, time spent on the Online Services, pages visited, referring URL, language preferences, and other aggregated traffic data. We use the data for security purposes, to facilitate navigation, to display data more effectively, to collect statistical data, to personalize your experience while using the Online Services and to recognize your computer to assist your use of the Online Services. We also gather statistical data about use of the Online Services to continually improve design and functionality, understand how they are used and assist us with resolving questions.

Cookies further allow us to select which advertisements or offers are most likely to appeal to you and display them while you are using the Online Services or to send marketing emails. We also use cookies to track responses to online advertisements and marketing emails

If you do not want data collected with cookies, you can learn more about controlling cookies at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookes/index.htm.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookes/index.htm)

You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings on your browser or by managing your tracking preferences by clicking on “Tracking Preferences” located at the bottom of our home page. If, however, you do not accept cookies, you may experience some inconvenience in your use of the Online Services. For example, we will not be able to recognize your computer, and you will need to log in every time you visit. You also will not receive advertising or other offers from us that are relevant to your interests and needs. At this time, we do not respond to browser “Do-Not-Track” signals

  * **Pixel Tags and other similar technologies.** We collect data from pixel tags (also known as web beacons and clear GIFs), which are used with some Online Services to, among other things, track the actions of users of the Online Services (including email recipients), measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about usage of the Online Services.
  * **Analytics.** We collect data through Google Analytics and Adobe Analytics, which use cookies and technologies to collect and analyze data about use of the Services. These services collect data regarding the use of other websites, apps and online resources. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/) and opt out by downloading the Google Analytics opt out browser add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. You can learn more about Adobe and opt out by visiting <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html>.
  * **Adobe Flash technology (such as Flash Local Shared Objects (“Flash LSOs”)) and other similar technologies.** We collect data through Flash LSOs and other technologies on some Websites to, among other things, collect and store data about your use of the Online Services. If you do not want Flash LSOs stored on your computer, you can adjust the settings of your Flash player to block Flash LSO storage using the tools contained in the Website Storage Settings Panel at <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>. You can also control Flash LSOs by going to the Global Storage Settings Panel at <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager03.html> and following the instructions (which include instructions that explain, for example, how to delete existing Flash LSOs (referred to as “information” on the Macromedia site), how to prevent Flash LSOs from being placed on your computer without your being asked, and (for Flash Player 8 and later) how to block Flash LSOs that are not being delivered by the operator of the page you are on at the time). Please note that setting the Flash Player to restrict or limit acceptance of Flash LSOs may reduce or impede the functionality of some Flash applications, including those used with the Online Services. For more information, please refer to <https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html>. 
  * **Your IP Address.** We collect your IP address, a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet Service Provider (ISP). An IP address is identified and logged automatically in our server log files when a user accesses the Online Services, along with the time of the visit and the pages that were visited. We use IP addresses to calculate usage levels, diagnose server problems and administer the Online Services. We also may derive your approximate location from your IP address.
  * **Aggregated Data.** We may aggregate data that we collected and this aggregated data will not personally identify you or any other user.

Back to Top

## Use of Personal Data and Other Data

We use Personal Data and Other Data to provide you with Services, to develop new offerings and to protect the Marriott Group and our guests as detailed below. In some instances, we will request that you provide Personal Data or Other Data to us directly. If you do not provide the data that we request, or prohibit us from collecting such data, we may not be able to provide the requested Services.

We use Personal Data and Other Data for our legitimate business interests, including the following:

  * **Provide the Services you request.** We use Personal Data and Other Data to provide Services you request, including: 
    * To facilitate reservations, payment, send administrative information, confirmations or pre-arrival messages, to assist you with meetings and events and to provide you with other information about the area and the property at which you are scheduled to visit
    * To complete your reservation and stay, for example, to process your payment, ensure that your room is available and provide you with related customer service
    * To support our electronic receipt program. When you provide an email address in making a reservation, we use that email address to send you a copy of your bill. If you make a reservation for another person using your email address, that person's bill will be emailed to you, as well. You can opt out of receiving your bill via email and instead receive a paper copy by contacting the front desk

We will use Personal Data and Other Data to manage our contractual relationship with you, because we have a legitimate interest to do so and/or to comply with a legal obligation.

  * **Personalize the Services according to your Personal Preferences.** We use Personal Data and Other Data to personalize the Services and improve your experiences, including when you contact our call center, visit one of our properties or use the Online Services, to: 
    * Customize your experience according to your Personal Preferences
    * Present offers tailored to your Personal Preferences

We will use Personal Data and Other Data to provide personalized Services according to your Personal Preferences either with your consent or because we have a legitimate interest to do so.

  * **Communicate with you about goods and services according to your Personal Preferences.** We use Personal Data and Other Data to: 
    * Send you marketing communications and promotional offers, as well as periodic customer satisfaction, market research or quality assurance surveys

We will use Personal Data and Other Data to communicate with you with your consent, to manage our contractual relationship with you and/or because we have a legitimate interest to do so.

  * **Loyalty Programs.** We use Personal Data and Other Data to: 
    * Offer and manage your participation in our global loyalty programs, as well as others that are specific to certain properties or tailored to your interests 
    * Send you offers, promotions and information about your account status and activities
    * Assess your benefits
    * Administer points earned through co-branded credit cards
    * Manage your choices regarding how you wish to earn, track and use your points

We will use Personal Data and Other Data in this way with your consent, to manage our contractual relationship with you and/or because we have a legitimate interest to do so.

  * **Sweepstakes, activities, events and promotions.** We use Personal Data and Other Data to allow you to participate in sweepstakes, contests and other promotions and to administer these activities. Some of these activities have additional rules and may contain additional information about how we use and disclose your Personal Data. We suggest that you read any such rules carefully.

We use Personal Data and Other Data in this way with your consent, to manage our contractual relationship with you and/or because we have a legitimate interest to do so.

  * **Business Purposes.** We use Personal Data and Other Data for data analysis, audits, security and fraud monitoring and prevention (including with the use of closed circuit television, card keys, and other security systems), developing new goods and services, enhancing, improving or modifying our Services, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and operating and expanding our business activities.

We use Personal Data and Other Data in this way to manage our contractual relationship with you, comply with a legal obligation and/or because we have a legitimate interest to do so.

Back to Top

## Disclosure of Personal Data and Other Data

Our goal is to provide you with the highest level of hospitality and Services, and to do so, we share Personal Data and Other Data with the following:

  * **Marriott Group.** We disclose Personal Data and Other Data to other companies within the [Marriott Group](http://www.marriott.com/Media/PDF/Foreign%20Subsidiaries%20-%20Country%20of%20Incorporation/2015%2010K_Entity%20Only.pdf) for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement, such as providing and personalizing the Services, communicating with you, facilitating the loyalty programs, and to accomplish our business purposes. Marriott International, Inc. is the party responsible for the management of the jointly-used Personal Data. We share your Personal Data and Other Data used for making a reservation with the applicable property to fulfill and complete your reservation. 
  * **Owners and Franchisees.** We disclose Personal Data and Other Data to Owners and Franchisees of Marriott Group branded properties for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement, such as providing and personalizing the Services and facilitating the loyalty programs.
  * **Authorized Licensees.** We disclose Personal Data and Other Data to our Authorized Licensees for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement, such as providing and personalizing the Services and fulfilling your requests. For example, this sharing enables you to purchase Marriott branded goods and services, including time share properties.
  * **Strategic Business Partners.** We disclose Personal Data and Other Data with select Strategic Business Partners who provide goods, services and offers that enhance your experience at our properties or that we believe will be of interest to you. By sharing data with these Strategic Business Partners, we are able to make personalized services and unique travel experiences available to you. For example, this sharing enables spa, restaurant, health club, concierge and other outlets at our properties to provide you with services. This sharing also enables us to provide you with a single source for purchasing packages that include travel-related services, such as airline tickets, rental cars and vacation packages. 
  * **Service Providers.** We disclose Personal Data and Other Data to third-party service providers for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement. Examples of service providers include companies that provide website hosting, data analysis, payment processing, order fulfillment, information technology and related infrastructure provision, customer service, email delivery, marketing, auditing and other services.
  * **Linked Accounts and Promotional Activity.** We partner with certain third parties that allow you to enroll in their services or participate in their promotions. For example, certain companies allow you to use your loyalty program number or Online Services login to receive or register for their services. These companies include airlines and rental car providers, as well as sponsors of sweepstakes and contests. Additionally, your social media account provider allows you to connect your social media account to your Online Services account or log into your Online Services account from your social media account. When you enroll in those services, we disclose your Personal Data and Other Data to those third parties. If you do not want us to share your Personal Data or Other Data in this way, do not provide your loyalty program number to third parties, do not use your Online Services login to register for third-party promotions and do not connect your Online Services account with accounts on third-party services. Data shared in this way will be governed by the third party’s privacy policy and not this Privacy Statement. 
  * **eFolio Program.** If you are an employee of a company that participates in the Marriott Group eFolio Program and book your room using a company corporate code or pay for your expenses using a corporate credit card, an extract of your folio detailing the goods and services provided to you may be sent to your company and to the credit card company. This Privacy Statement does not apply to the handling of your Personal Data by your employer, and any credit card company or bank, and we are not responsible for their practices.
  * **Corporate Reorganization.** We may disclose or transfer your Personal Data and Other Data to a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of the Marriott Group business, assets or stock (including any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

Back to Top

## Other Uses and Disclosures

We will use and disclose Personal Data as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) to comply with applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities, including authorities outside your country of residence and to meet national security or law enforcement requirements; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations; (f) to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of the Marriott Group, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

We may use and disclose Other Data for any purpose, except where we are not allowed to under applicable law. In some instances, we may combine Other Data with Personal Data (such as combining your name with your location). If we do, we will treat the combined data as Personal Data as long as it is combined.

Back to Top

## Non-Marriott Group Entities

This Privacy Statement does not address, and we are not responsible for the privacy, data or other practices of any entities outside of the Marriott Group, including Franchisees, Owners, Authorized Licensees, Strategic Business Partners or any third party operating any site or service to which the Services link, payment service, loyalty program, or website that is the landing page of the high-speed Internet providers at our properties. The inclusion of a link on the Online Services does not imply endorsement of the linked site or service by us. We have no control over, and are not responsible for, any third party’s collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Data.

In addition, we are not responsible for the data collection, use, disclosure or security policies or practices of other organizations, such as Facebook, Apple, Google, Microsoft, RIM or any other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider or device manufacturer, including with respect to any Personal Data you disclose to other organizations through or the Apps or our Social Media Pages. 

Back to Top

## Third Party Advertisers

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements regarding goods and services that may interest you when you access and use the Online Services, other websites or online services. To serve such advertisements, these companies place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser (including through use of pixel tags). If you would like more information about this practice, and to learn about your choices in connection with it, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> and <http://www.aboutads.info/>. To opt out of the practice, you may download the AppChoices app at www.aboutads.info/appchoices.

Back to Top

## Security

We seek to use reasonable organizational, technical and administrative measures to protect Personal Data. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of your account has been compromised), please immediately notify us in accordance with the _“Contacting Us”_ section, below.

Back to Top

## LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES:

In order to anticipate your needs, our website provides links to other web sites and third parties for your convenience and information. We are not responsible for the collection, use, maintenance, sharing or disclosure of data (including personal data) by such third parties. We encourage you to contact these third parties to ask questions about their privacy practices, policies and security measures before disclosing any personal data. We recommend that you review the privacy statements and policies of linked web sites to understand how those web sites collect, use and store information.

Back to Top

## Choices, Access and Retention

You have choices when it comes to how we use your data and we want to ensure you have the information to make the choices that are right for you. 

If you no longer want to receive marketing-related emails, you may opt out by visiting our [unsubscribe page](https://www.marriott.com/profile/email/unsubscribeChallenge.mi) at https://www.marriott.com/profile/email/unsubscribeChallenge.mi or by following the instructions in any such email you receive from us

In addition, members of our loyalty programs can opt out from marketing-related emails through their program account, or by sending a letter to: Internet Customer Care – Unsubscribe, 1818 North 90 Street, Omaha, Nebraska 68114-1315 USA.

We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. If you opt out of receiving marketing emails from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, from which you cannot opt out.

**Special Notice for California Residents:** Customers who reside in California and have provided their Personal Data to us can request, once per calendar year, information about our sharing of certain categories of Personal Data to third parties and within the Marriott Group, for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests should be submitted to us at [privacy@marriott.com](mailto:privacy@marriott.com) or:

Marriott International, Inc.  
Global Compliance, Privacy  
10400 Fernwood Road  
Bethesda, MD 20817  

We will provide a list of the categories of Personal Data disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, along with the names and addresses of these third parties. We reserve our right not to respond to requests submitted to addresses other than the addresses specified in this paragraph. 

Back to Top

## How You Can Access, Change or Suppress Your Personal Data

If you would like to review, correct, update, suppress, restrict or delete Personal Data that you have previously provided to us, or if you would like to receive an electronic copy of your Personal Data for purposes of transmitting it to another company (to the extent this right to data portability is provided to you by law), you can contact us at [privacy@marriott.com](mailto:privacy@marriott.com), or by mail:

Marriott International, Inc.  
Global Compliance, Privacy  
10400 Fernwood Road  
Bethesda, MD 20817  

In your request, please make clear what Personal Data you would like to have changed, whether you would like to have your Personal Data suppressed from our database, or other limitations you would like to put on our use of your Personal Data. For your protection, we only fulfill requests for the Personal Data associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before fulfilling your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. 

Please note that we often need to retain certain data for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting a change or deletion (e.g., when you make a purchase or reservation, or enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Data provided until after the completion of such purchase, reservation, or promotion). There may also be residual data that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed. In addition, there may be certain data that we may not allow you to review for legal, security or other reasons.

Back to Top

### Retention

We will retain your Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Statement unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. 

The criteria used to determine our retention periods include: 

  * The length of time we have an ongoing relationship with you and provide the Services to you (for example, for as long as you have an account with us or keep using the Services)
  * Whether there is a legal obligation to which we are subject (for example, certain laws require us to keep records of your transactions for a certain period of time before we can delete them)
  * Whether retention is advisable considering our legal position (such as, for statutes of limitations, litigation or regulatory investigations)

Back to Top

## Sensitive Data

Unless specifically requested, we ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, on or through the Services or otherwise to us, any Sensitive Personal Data (e.g., social security numbers, national identification number, data related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion, ideological or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background, trade union membership, or administrative or criminal proceedings and sanctions).

Back to Top

## Use of Services by Minors

The Services are not directed to individuals under the age of sixteen (16), and we request that they not provide Personal Data through the Services.

Back to Top

## Cross-Border Transfer

The Marriott Group is a global organization and provides a global service. Sharing data cross-border is essential to the Services so that you receive the same high-quality service wherever you are in the world. As a result, we will, subject to law, transfer Personal Data and Other Data collected in connection with the Services, to entities in countries where data protection standards may differ from those in the country where you reside. By making a reservation, visiting or staying at a Marriott branded property or using any Marriott Group branded service, you understand that we transfer your Personal Data globally. 

In certain circumstances, courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other countries will be entitled to access your Personal Data. 

Some of the non-EEA countries are recognized by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of data protection according to EEA standards (the full list of these countries is available [here](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en)). 

Back to Top

## Privacy Shield Certified

Marriott International, Inc. and certain of its U.S. affiliates have certified to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield frameworks. Our certifications can be found at: [www.privacyshield.gov/list](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). For more information about the Privacy Shield principles, please visit: www.privacyshield.gov. Our Privacy Shield Guest Privacy Policy can be found here.

Back to Top

## Updates to This Privacy Statement

The _“LAST UPDATED”_ legend at the top of this page indicates when this Privacy Statement was last revised. Any changes will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Statement on the Online Services. Your use of the Services following these changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Statement. If you would like to review the version of the Privacy Statement that was effective immediately prior to this revision, please contact us at privacy@marriott.com. 

Back to Top

## Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at privacy@marriott.com, or by mail:

Marriott International, Inc.  
Global Compliance, Privacy  
10400 Fernwood Road  
Bethesda, MD 20817  

For additional information about our complaints management practices and contacts, please refer to our Privacy Shield Guest Privacy Policy. Because your email communications to us may not always be secure, please do not include credit card or Sensitive Data in your emails to us. 

Back to Top

## Additional Information

You also can:

  * Contact our data protection officer responsible for your country or region via MarriottDPO@marriott.com. In your email, please indicate the country from which you are contacting us
  * Lodge a complaint with a data protection authority for your country or region or where an alleged infringement of applicable data protection laws occurs at <http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080>.

Back to Top

## Privacy Preferences

At Marriott, we respect your privacy and want to provide you with information and choices. The options provided below allow you to express your preferences: what and how much you share with us and when and how you hear from us.

## Cookie Preferences

We want to learn what is relevant to you and ensure you have a personalized experience. As described in more detail in our Global Privacy Statement, we use digital tools like cookies and tags on our webpages. Cookies also help us provide, protect and improve our services.

To adjust your preferences, please visit our Tracking Preferences page.

Back to Top

## Marketing Preferences

We want to engage with you in a way that is meaningful to you. We recognize that you may only want to hear from us in a limited way.

To adjust your preferences, please visit your loyalty account profile and click on [“Communication Preferences,”](https://www.starwoodhotels.com/preferredguest/account/profile/update_email_options.html) or you also may choose to “unsubscribe” by clicking the link at the bottom of one our communications.

*Please note that even if you choose to opt-out of communications with us, we will continue to send you transactional messages about your specific reservation or stay with us, such as pre-arrival, confirmation and guest satisfaction surveys.

Back to Top

## Other Preferences

If you have other preferences, or are looking to exercise your rights under the GDPR, please email us at Privacy@Marriott.com, or mail us at:

Marriott International, Inc.  
Global Compliance, Privacy  
10400 Fernwood Road   
Bethesda, MD 20817  
United States of America  

We will work with you to understand and process your request. Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before taking further action on your request.

Back to Top

Marriott International, Inc. and the U.S. affiliates listed at the end of this Policy (“Marriott U.S.”) have created this Privacy Shield Privacy Policy to help you learn about how we handle Guest Personal Data that we receive from our affiliates, Owners and Franchisees located in the European Economic Area (the “EEA”) and Switzerland under the Privacy Shield program. This Privacy Shield Privacy Policy supplements the Marriott Group Global Privacy Statement. Unless specifically defined differently in this Policy, the capitalized terms in this Privacy Shield Privacy Policy have the same meaning as in the Marriott Group Global Privacy Statement.

Marriott U.S. has subscribed to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield programs (“Privacy Shield”) and is committed to adhering to the Privacy Shield Principles, which include the Supplemental Principles (collectively, the “Principles”) for all Guest Personal Data received from the EEA and Switzerland. More information about Privacy Shield can be found at: https://www.privacyshield.gov; and the list of certified organizations can be found at: www.privacyshield.gov/list.

### Personal Data Received From the EEA and Switzerland

Marriott U.S. may receive Personal Data from entities in the EEA and Switzerland such as:

  * Name, gender, home and work address, telephone number and email address, your business title, date and place of birth, income, nationality, language, passport and visa or other government-issued identification data;
  * Biometric data, consistent with applicable law;
  * Data about family members and companions, such as names and ages of children;
  * Important dates, including birthdays, anniversaries and special occasions;
  * Guest preferences and personalized data (“Personal Preferences”), including:
    * data concerning your interests, activities and hobbies, food and beverage choices, fitness activities, hobbies and services and amenities of which you advise us or which we learn about during your visit;
  * Telephone numbers dialed, faxes sent/received or receipt of telephone messages we provide guests during their visit or stay;
  * For purposes of quality assurance and training, conversations between you and our representatives;
  * Credit and debit card number or other payments data;
  * Membership or loyalty programs data (including co-branded payment cards or other co-branded programs), online user accounts details, profile or password details and any frequent flyer or travel partner program affiliation;
  * Employer or other relevant details if you are an employee of a corporate account, a vendor or other type of business partner (e.g., travel agent or meeting and event planner);
  * Additional contact data about you that we sometimes obtain through third parties with whom we do business (e.g., travel agents or similar providers);
  * Travel itinerary and tour or activity group data;
  * Social media account ID or user ID, profile photo and other data you make available publicly or to us from your social media accounts, publically available platforms or other sources. (collectively, “Personal Data”). 

## Use of Personal Data

Any Personal Data sent to us may be used by Marriott U.S. and its Service Providers for the purposes indicated in the Marriott Group Global Privacy Statement. If we intend to use your Personal Data for a purpose that is materially different from these purposes or if we intend to disclose it to a third party not previously identified, we will notify you and offer you the opportunity to opt-out of such uses and/or disclosures where it involves Personal Data or opt-in where Sensitive Personal Data is involved. 

## Disclosures to Affiliates and Third Parties

Your Personal Data may be disclosed to the following:

  * To the Marriott Group for the purposes described in this Policy;
  * To Service Providers;
  * To third parties offering offering travel, hospitality, entertainment, and other services to enhance your experience, such as Franchisees, Owners of managed properties, Authorized Licensees, and Strategic Business Partners; 
  * To your employer or the credit card company if you participate in the Marriott Group’s eFolio Program; 
  * To third-party sponsors of sweepstakes, contests and similar promotions;
  * To a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

## Disclosures to Service Providers

We sometimes contract with other companies and individuals to perform functions or services on our behalf such as spas and restaurants within our hotels, website hosting, data analysis, payment processing, order fulfillment, information technology and related infrastructure provision, customer service, email delivery, auditing and other services. They may have access to Personal Data needed to perform their functions, but are restricted from using the Personal Data for purposes other than providing services for us or to us. Marriott U.S. requires that its Service Providers that have access to Personal Data received from the EEA and Switzerland provide the same level of protection as required by the Privacy Shield Principles. We are responsible for ensuring that our Service Providers process the Personal Data in a manner consistent with our obligations under the Principles.

## Data Security

We use reasonable physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to protect your Personal Data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, taking into account the nature of the Personal Data and the risks involved in processing that information.

## Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation

We limit the collection and use of Personal Data to the information that is relevant for the purposes of processing and will not process Personal Data in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which the information has been collected or subsequently authorized by you. We take reasonable steps to ensure the Personal Data is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current to the extent necessary for the purposes for which we use the Personal Data.

## Access to Personal Data

You can ask to review, correct, or delete Personal Data that we maintain about you by sending a written request to privacy@marriott.com.

## Privacy Shield Enforcement and Dispute Resolution

If you have any questions or concerns, please write to us at the address listed below. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of Personal Data in accordance with the Privacy Shield Principles.

If we are unable to resolve your complaints or disputes, you may contact JAMS and they will investigate and assist you, free of charge, in resolving your complaint. Please refer to: [https://www.jamsadr.com](https://www.jamsadr.com/) for more information.

As further explained in the Privacy Shield Principles, a binding arbitration option will also be made available to you in order to address residual complaints not resolved by any other means. Marriott U.S. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

## Disclosures Required By Law

We may need to disclose Personal Data in response to lawful requests by public authorities for law enforcement or national security reasons or when such action is necessary to comply with a judicial proceeding or court order, or when otherwise required by law.

## Contact Information

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Shield Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at privacy@marriott.com, or please write to the following address:

Marriott International, Inc.  
Global Compliance, Privacy  
10400 Fernwood Road  
Bethesda, MD 20817  
United States of America 

## Privacy Policy Changes

This Policy may be changed from time to time, consistent with the requirements of the Privacy Shield. You can determine when this Policy was last revised by referring to the "LAST UPDATED" legend at the top of this page. Any changes to our Policy will become effective upon our posting of the revised Policy on the Site.

## Marriott U.S. entities covered by this Policy

Marriott Hotel Services, Inc.  
Marriott International Administrative Services, Inc.  
Marriott Rewards, Inc.  
Marriott Worldwide Reservation Services, LLC   
Starwood Hotels & Resorts Management Company, LLC   
Starwood Hotels & Resorts Worldwide, LLC   
Starwood Reservations LLC   
The Ritz-Carlton Hotel Company, LLC  
Galaxy Hotel Systems LLC
